TIME 0300 OPERATION ROOM
（时间：三点，作战室）
Okonogi, what's the current status?
小此木，报告现况
Yes, ma'm. Evacuation has begun on neighboring residents from 0245.
是，已在0245开始疏散周边居民
TIME 0301 SAGAMIHARA
（时间：3点1分，相模原）
Emergency kaiju alert.
紧急怪兽警报…
The epicenter is Sagamihara.
震央位在相模原
Neighboring residents, please follow the JGSDF's instructions for evacuation.
周边居民 请遵守自卫队的指示进行避难
-I repeat. Neighboring residents… -Why Sagamihara?
-重复一次，周边居民… -为什么是相模原？
When's the JGSDF coming?
自卫队还没来吗？
Mommy, I want to pee.
妈妈，我想上厕所
Don't panic, please. The next vehicle is coming right away.
不要慌张，下一辆车马上就到了
Please remain calm. There will be enough buses.
请保持冷静，车辆非常充足
How's it going with Self Defense?
和自卫队的合作呢？
We're setting up a SDF Artillery
正在友旺梦乐城的停车场
Regiment Command Post in the Reon Mall parking lot.
设置自卫队特科连队指挥处
-FO is ready. -The observation area is set.
-前进指挥所展开 -观测所设置完成
What's the information on evacuation?
请求避难疏散的情报
How's the Honju?
主兽的状况呢？
After appearing at the Kannawa Fault, it's been growing and moving underground.
在神绳断层产生后 就在地底成长并同时移动
We suspect it appeared on the surface due to entering its breeding phase.
推测要进入增殖期后才会在地表现身
A large number of yoju have appeared along with the honju.
伴随主兽出现，也会有大量的余兽
Hey, just how many are there?
太夸张了，到底有多少啊？
Fortunately, the neutralization area isn't far.
还好讨伐区域并不远
Considering damages to the area,
考虑到对周边区域的损害
Area Bravo is best suited
我想在讨伐区域内侧的B地区
for the destruction of the honju.
歼灭主兽最适合
I'll take care of the honju.
主兽由我来处理
The shooting position will be Area Echo.
狙击点设在E区
That way, we can target the enemy along the Tokyo loop line.
在这里就能沿着 东京环状线来锁定敌人
This strategy will be named the Sagamihara Neutralization Operation.
这次作战将命名为相模原讨伐作战
Good luck, everyone.
祝各位好运
Are you ready?
做好觉悟了吗？
It's time to defeat the kaiju.
消灭怪兽的时间到了
Our first mission.
第一次任务…
Kaiju No.8.
怪兽8号…
I still can't believe it.
虽然我还不太相信
But don't let me down,
但最好别让我失望
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
Vice Captain! Senpai's about to throw up!
副队长！前辈好像要吐了！
I'm sorry. I ate too much from nerves.
对不起，我太紧张，吃太多了
-Most people can't eat from nerves! -Open the windows!
-通常是吃不下吧！ -快开窗户！
I'll kill you if you barf!
敢吐的话就宰了你！
-What's wrong with you? -Please, spare my life!
-大叔，你搞什么啊？ -饶命啊
TIME 0400 SDF 304 COMMAND POST REON MALL SAGAHIHARA PARKING LOT
（时间：四点；自卫队304指挥处 友旺梦乐城相模原店停车场）
SAME TIME: REON MALL SAGAMIHARA SHOP EVACUATION AREA
（同一时间 友旺梦乐城相模原店避难所）
SAME TIME GSDF ANTI KAIJU SPECIAL BATTALION
陆上自卫队对怪兽特科大队）
AREA E
（同一时间，E地区）
This is the neutralization area.
这里就是讨伐地区
And that is
那就是…
the honju we're dealing with.
这次的主兽
Here's the strategy.
开始说明作战计划
The honju will be dealt with by Captain Ashiro's platoon.
主兽由亚白队长率队处理
The problem is the yoju, which keeps being produced in large numbers.
问题是主兽生出的无数余兽
This neutralization area doesn't have
这个讨伐区域
the necessary facilities or major transportation for neutralization.
没有设置重要机关或交通要道
Your job
你们的工作
is to get rid of all the yoju in this area without letting them escape.
就是一个不漏地 将这区的余兽处理干净
It's an important task that greatly influences the damages
达成与否将会 影响损害范围、重建费用
and the time and cost of reconstruction if it fails.
还有所耗费的时间，是项重要的工作
Of course, the platoon, including newbies, will be placed at the very back.
有新人的小队当然会配置在最后
In other words,
换句话说
you're our last resort.
你们就是最后的防线
Any questions?
有问题吗？
All right.
很好
No matter how high you score during training,
在训练场就算取得多优异的成绩
it doesn't save a single life.
也救不了任何人
Show us your strength on the field, baby chicks.
在战场上展现实力吧，雏鸟们
All right, let's go!
好，上啊！
I'm counting on you.
那就拜托你们咯
This is the SDF Artillery Regiment Command Post.
这里是自卫队特科连队指挥处
We've evacuated all residents and set up an observation area.
居民疏散完毕，观测所设置完成
Roger that. We thank you for your help.
了解，感谢你们协助
All platoons and the SDF have completed preparation.
各小队与自卫队准备完毕
Three minutes until Captain Ashiro is ready.
亚白队长离准备完成还有8分钟
It's finally time, Senpai.
终于到这一步了，前辈
Yeah. I have to do good work here or else…
是啊，不趁这个机会好好表现的话…
Keep this up, and you'll never get promoted as an officer.
再这样下去，你没办法升格正式队员
You'll be fired in three months!
三个月后就会被开除哦
I have no future here.
…就没戏唱了
Nerves, panic.
紧张、焦虑
All kinds of pressure are on us.
各种压力排山倒海而来
So, why is it
但不知道为什么
that I'm so excited right now?
我兴奋到不行
It makes sense. It's the job he's wanted to do for so long.
这也难怪，毕竟是向往已久的工作
-Senpai. -Yeah?
-前辈 -嗯？
Let's make sure our first mission is a success!
第一次任务，一定要成功
Yeah.
没错
Confirmed yoju invasion in Area Echo!
E地区，确认到余兽入侵
They're here!
来了
Let's go, Kikoru.
我们上吧，琪歌露
Why are you ordering me around?
为什么是你在发号施令啊？
-Don't die, Ichikawa! -You too, Senpai!
-可别死啊，市川 -前辈才是吧
All right! Let's succeed at our first mission!
好，成功完成第一次任务吧！
Let's go!
上啊！
Captain Ashiro is now ready at the shooting point.
亚白队长已在狙击点就位
Please continue to lure the honju to Area Bravo and provide fire support.
请继续诱导主兽前往B区 同时提供火力支援
Roger that. This is the SDF Artillery Regiment Command Post.
了解，这里是自卫队特科连队指挥处
Initiating fire support for the Defense Force.
开始为防卫队提供火力支援
Their debut match has begun.
开始了呢，出道战
Knock our socks off, everyone.
就先让各位前辈吓破胆吧
It's begun.
开始了
But it's not like the exams at all.
但是和测验时不同
I feel oddly calm.
感觉莫名地冷静
I can feel the suit working with me.
我能感受到战斗服会回应我
Release full combat power!
战力解放！
Don't go to the front!
你跑太前面了！
You're a one-percenter, so, stay back, all right?
只有1%，还不快退到后面去！
Geez.
真是的
Why do we have to babysit the newbie officers?
为什么我们得当新人的保姆啊？
Just watch where you won't get in the way, okay?
拜托你们至少站在 不会碍事的位置好好看着
Listen up. We still don't know the enemy's weak spot.
听着，目前还不知道敌人的要害
Be careful until we get information from the frontlines.
在前线的家伙提供情报之前 要慎重地…
Yes, sir.
了解
We'll be careful and blow away all areas that look like weak spots.
慎重地把疑似要害的地方全部打穿
What the hell?!
怎么回事？
That's not the power of someone who joined a month ago.
这可不是入队一两个月该有的威力啊
So, that's Kikoru Shinomiya, huh?
这就是四之宫琪歌露吗？
Kikoru!
琪歌露！
Nice job!
干得好！
Of course I did a nice job! It's me!
当然咯，你以为我是谁啊？
Irregular vitals. Sudden increase in heart rate.
生命体征异常，心跳数急速上升
Don't make such unnecessary reports!
这点小事不用报告！
AREA F
（F地区）
All right, I've taken out two legs. Finish it off.
好，打掉两只脚了，解决它们
Great job, Furuhashi!
古桥，干得好
All right! You see that, Reno?
好耶，你看到了吗，雷诺？
Did you do that without an assist?
那只…是你自己干掉的？
Yes.
对
I changed the bullet from burst rounds to freeze rounds.
我试着将子弹的特性从炸裂换成冻结
This works better for me. I can slow down the enemy and fight.
能在战斗中让敌人的动作迟缓 或许比较适合我的个性
If I get used to this, I can hunt better than this!
要是掌握诀窍 应该能更有效地狩猎怪兽
Not yet. I have to be stronger,
不够，我必须变得更强
so Senpai doesn't have to transform.
要强大到让前辈不用变身
AREA J
（J地区）
Stay still!
源源不绝啊
What's going on with this year's newbies?
今年的新人有什么问题啊？
Platoon Leader Nakanoshima! What's with them?
中之岛小队长，那些人是怎样啊？
I'm losing my confidence!
我快丧失自信了
I knew we had some good people this year, but I didn't expect this.
有听说今年是大丰收 但没想到这么优秀
I've already killed six.
我已经打倒六只了
You're a bit slow, Haruichi.
你是不是速度有点慢，阳一？
Okay, okay.
对啦
Don't forget that four of those were assisted by me.
你别忘了有四只是我帮忙打倒的
One's a wild type, one's a cool, nice guy type.
一个狂野型，一个爽朗型
LOVES MEN
（肉食女）
-Yup, we sure got some good ones! -You mean their looks?
-今年确实是大丰收 -原来是长相吗？
I heard there were a few exceptional ones from Vice Captain Hoshino,
保科副队长说有几个人特别突出
but that's not all.
看来收获不只如此啊
The average unleashed combat power is high among the newbies.
跟往年比 新人的平均解放战力高上许多
The high-achievers are making everyone level up.
可能是在高材生的带领下 拉高了整体水平
-Eighth one down! -That was mine!
-第八只 -刚刚那是我的！
Observation team, Area Juliet. Confirmed zero yoju in the area.
观测班，确认J地区没有余兽
All yoju are defeated.
已歼灭所有余兽
Reports after reports of completed yoju destructions. Everyone's so impressive.
接二连三收到打倒怪兽的报告 大家都好厉害
Platoon Ikaruga invading with Ichikawa and Furuhashi at the lead.
斑鸠小队、市川和古桥带头进攻
Ichikawa and Iharu, too!
市川和伊春也有
This isn't good. Everyone's working hard, and I'm only a burden.
不行，大家这么努力 我不能只扯后腿
Is there anything I can do?
有没有什么我能做的？
Wait, if I remember correctly…
对了，刚才…
Listen up. We still don't know the enemy's weak spot.
听着，目前还不知道敌人的要害
Be careful until we get information from the frontlines.
在前线的家伙提供情报之前 要慎重地…
I'll use my own weapon.
我要…用自己的武器战斗
Senpai, look there!
前辈，那边
What the hell is he doing?
那家伙在干嘛啊？
It's easy to take apart with the suit, even at 1%.
就算只有1% 在战斗服的帮忙下也很容易解体
Could they distribute these to cleanup sites
要是产能再高一点
once they're easier to mass produce?
能不能也卖给解体业者啊？
It's a common fungal-type kaiju structure.
这是菌类系怪兽常见的构造
But its core isn't where it usually is.
但通常有核心的位置却没东西
Where is it? If not here, is it here?
在哪里？这边没有，会在那里吗？
What? Is this…?
咦？这是…
-Vice Captain Hoshino! I found the core! -What?
-保科副队长，我找到核心的位置了 -什么？
It's at the base of the neck.
在颈部的底部
But it's located under a hard muscle fiber that acts as the spine.
但它长在作为脊椎的硬纤维肌底下
So, officers with low attacking power might have to shoot from the side.
攻击力较低的队员 不从侧面攻击，可能无法伤到核心
I see.
哦？
And another thing. This is more important.
还有一点，这很重要
The yoju have reproductive organs, too.
余兽也有增殖器官
It's the white, bumpy organ at the butt.
在臀部附近，白色凹凸不平的器官
If we don't destroy these, more yoju might be born from the dead bodies.
不破坏的话，余兽的尸体 搞不好会生出新的余兽
Kafka. Great work.
卡夫卡，你立大功了
Okonogi-chan. Please share that information with all officers.
小此木，把刚才的情报 转达给所有队员
Roger! I'll share the data about the yoju's core and reproductive organs.
了解，已经分享 余兽的核心和增殖器官资料
Your previous job experience helped,
不只活用前一份工作的经验
but it's because you studied hard every day.
也发挥了平常学习的成果
Well done.
你做得很好
I was useful for the Defense Force?
我对防卫队做出贡献了？
I'm going to disable all the dead bodies one by one.
我去破坏那些尸体的增殖器官
I'll do anything I can do.
能力所及的我都会做
Until I reach
直到抵达…
the position next to Mina…
米娜的身边为止
-What is it? -They've started.
-怎么了？ -那边也开始了啊
Honju has reached the predicted enemy engagement area.
主兽抵达预计接战地点
Requesting the SDF to withdraw.
请自卫队航空队撤退
The Defense Force has begun attacking on the leg of the honju.
防卫队开始对主兽脚部进行攻击
Please demobilize the honju as much as possible.
请尽可能阻止主兽行动
Target captured. Coriolis has completed gravity effect corrections.
目标锁定 科氏力，重力效果补正完毕
No shooting attack target in the area.
周边不存在对狙击手的威胁对象
First bullet is locked and loaded.
第一弹装填完毕
Roger. All clear on shooting conditions.
了解，狙击条件状况良好
Begin shooting now.
开始射击
Let's bet on who becomes the coolest Defense Force officer!
我们来比赛谁能成为帅气的队员吧
Kafka-kun.
卡夫卡
This is who I am now.
这就是现在的我
Unleashed combat power, 96%.
战力解放96%
Watch carefully, Kafka.
卡夫卡，看清楚了
This is…
这就是…
the power of the person you're working to stand next to.
你想要并肩之人的力量
-Second bullet is locked and loaded. -Roger. Begin shooting.
-第二弹装填完毕 -了解，开始射击
Honju's vital responses have disappeared. It's collapsing!
主兽的活体反应消失，要倒下了
-Third bullet is locked and loaded. -Roger. Begin shooting.
-第三弹装填完毕 -了解，开始射击
Honju has been destroyed! All movements have stopped.
主兽已摧毁，彻底停止活动
As expected of Captain.
真不愧是队长
Fourth bullet is locked and loaded.
第四弹装填完毕
-But the honju has already been silenced… -Please provide the command.
-但是主兽已经没反应… -下达指令
Roger!
了解
Damn. It's different from seeing it on TV or through binoculars.
可恶，这跟透过电视或 望远镜看到的完全不一样
She's tremendously strong!
那家伙果然不得了！
You ready to give up now?
想放弃了吗？
To stand next to her means
要跟她并肩作战
you have to have that much power.
就代表要拥有同等的力量
You say that, but can you do what she did, Vice Captain Hoshino?
这样说的话 保科副队长也能做到那样吗？
-No way. -"No way"?
-办不到 -办不到哦？
I have a low unleashed combat power for shooting weapons,
我操作狙击武器的解放战力太低
so, I can't beat Captain Ashiro when dealing with the big ones.
无法像亚白队长那样对付大型怪兽
But with the small and mid-sized kaiju…
相对的，要是对付中小型怪兽…
Vice Captain, behind you!
副队长，后面！
I'm better at these than her.
应该是我更胜一筹
A sword?
刀？
He was so fast, I couldn't see his movements.
动作快到完全看不见
I come from a long line of kaiju neutralizers since the Muromachi era.
我来自室町时代 延续至今的怪兽讨伐队一族
I'm better at this stuff.
所以更擅长用刀
Captains and Vice Captains are the strongest in the division.
队长和副队长是部队的最强战力
They provide unique equipment to suit your fighting style.
因此会配备适合个人特质的专用装备
-Hoshina. I'm done with the honju. -Roger.
-保科，已经解决主兽了 -了解
We're done talking here. The real fight's about to begin.
就闲聊到这里吧，重头戏要开始了
But they defeated the honju.
但刚刚不是说打倒主兽了…
I told you. The problem is the large number of yoju being born.
我说过了吧？问题是大量增殖的余兽
Even with the honju's dead, the remaining yoju left in its dead body…
就算解决掉主兽 尸体中残留的余兽…
Just as expected.
不出所料
They're coming.
要来了
…will flood out at the end.
…最后会一涌而出
All right, everyone. This is the big finale.
好了，各位，要收尾了
Once we kick those away, let's go home and have a good breakfast.
把那些家伙打发掉 就能回去吃早餐了
Kick them away? He makes it sound so easy!
打发？说得倒简单
You're already beat, newbies? Your stamina isn't quite there yet.
新人已经累垮了吗？ 你们的体力还差得远呢！
You bastards! Show them that fighting isn't just about
小子们，战斗不是只靠解放战力
unleashed combat power!
让新人见识看看！
-Yes, sir!
-是
-Hey, you two. -Platoon Leader Nakanoshima.
-你们两个 -中之岛小队长
You could leave everything to your senpai
后面就交给前辈们
and take a break. What do you want to do?
你们去休息也可以哦，如何啊？
-We're going, of course!
-当然要战斗了
OPERATION MEMBER OFFICERS ACTIVITY INFORMATION
（作战配置队员活动状况）
The newbies are getting tired.
新人们都很累了呢
Both their activity levels and combat powers are going down.
活动力和解放战力都下降了
It's a pretty laborious neutralization for a first mission.
以第一次任务来说 这次讨伐相当吃力嘛
But once they get through this,
但要是能挺过这关
they might grow even more.
就有可能再次脱胎换骨
Most officers' unleashed combat power stops at 20% to 30%.
大部分队员的 解放战力都停在20%到30%
They remain at the officer level until retirement.
以一般队员的身份结束生涯
But there are a few talents that get over that barrier and become captain level.
仅有少部分人 才能跨越障碍，成长到队长等级
This year, only Kikoru Shinomiya got over that barrier.
今年的新人只有 四之宫琪歌露跨过了那道障碍
But I see that potential
但我在另一个人…
in Reno Ichikawa, as well.
市川雷诺身上也感受到那种潜力
Shit, I trained hard for five years
可恶，我可是在讨伐专科学校
at technical college!
受过五年扎实训练
Why can't I keep up with him?
为什么却还跟不上这家伙？
Iharu-kun. Looks like there are no more yoju here.
伊春，看来这里已经没有余兽了
Yeah, looks like it.
对，看来是这样
Confirmed yoju invasion at Area Foxtrot.
F地区确认到余兽入侵
-They're here! Let's go back! -Yeah.
-来了，我们回去战斗吧 -哦！
Monster Sweeper?
怪兽清扫有限公司？
Why is there a cleaner here?
为什么这里会有解体作业员？
Hey, you didn't hear the alert?
喂，你没听到警报吗？
Cleanup will be done later.
还不到解体业者进来的时候
Him, too.
这家伙也一样
The reproductive organ I placed has been destroyed.
埋进去的增殖器官被破坏了
How did they find out?
为什么会被看穿呢？
Is there an officer with extensive kaiju knowledge?
队员里是不是有很了解怪兽的人啊？
You know anything about it?
你有什么头绪吗？
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：唐咏杰